<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <rdf:Description>
    <dc:title>From prehistory to history [electronic resource] : shared perspectives in Australian heritage interpretation /</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>Batten, Bronwyn.</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>Macquarie University.Warawara - Dept. of Indigenous Studies.</dc:creator>
    <dc:type manuscript="yes">text</dc:type>
    <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2005.</dc:date>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:description>It has long been established that in Australia contemporary (post-contact) Aboriginal history has suffered as a result of the colonisation process.  Aboriginal history was seen as belonging in the realm of prehistory, rather than in contemporary historical discourses.  Attempts have now been made to reinstate indigenous history into local, regional and national historical narratives.  The field of heritage interpretation however, still largely relegates Aboriginal heritage to prehistory.  Aboriginal heritage is seen as being a separate interpretive field from 'historic heritage', and is often linked to 'natural heritage'.  This thesis invetigates the ways in which Aborigianl history can be incorporated into the interpetation of contemporary or post-contact history at heritage sites.  The thesis uses the principle of 'shared history' as outlined by the Council for Aboriginal Reconciliation, as a starting point in these discussions.  However, the ultimate aim is to go beyond this definition.  By investigating a variety of heritage sites (examples are taken from monuments, museums and historic sites Australia wide), and in particular those that are attempting to</dc:description>
    <dc:description>incorporate both indigenous and non-indigenous history in their interpretive programs, this thesis argues for effective ways to create 'shared histories' in practice, whilst also analysing the problems that can be encountered when trying to establish these programs.  The resulting discussion provides insights, particularly for those working in the field of interpretation, as to how heritage interpreters in Australia can adopt a more inclusive approach, that is, an approach that allows for multiple voices both from and about the past, to be heard.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Thesis (PhD)--Macquarie University (Division of Society, Culture, Media &amp; Philosophy, Warawara - Department of Indigenous Studies), 2005.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Bibliography: p. 248-265.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Introduction and method -- General issues in heritage interpretation: Monuments and memorials; Museums; Other issues -- Historic site case studies: Parramatta Park and Old Government House; The Meeting Place Precinct - Botany Bay National Park; Myall Creek -- Discussion and conclusions.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>It has long been established that in Australia contemporary (post-contact) Aboriginal history has suffered as a result of the colonisation process.  Aboriginal history was seen as belonging in the realm of prehistory, rather than in contemporary historical discourses.  Attempts have now been made to reinstate indigenous history into local, regional and national historical narratives.  The field of heritage interpretation however, still largely relegates Aboriginal heritage to prehistory.  Aboriginal heritage is seen as being a separate interpretive field from 'historic heritage', and is often linked to 'natural heritage'.  This thesis invetigates the ways in which Aborigianl history can be incorporated into the interpetation of contemporary or post-contact history at heritage sites.  The thesis uses the principle of 'shared history' as outlined by the Council for Aboriginal Reconciliation, as a starting point in these discussions.  However, the ultimate aim is to go beyond this definition.  By investigating a variety of heritage sites (examples are taken from monuments, museums and historic sites Australia wide), and in particular those that are attempting to</dc:description>
    <dc:description>incorporate both indigenous and non-indigenous history in their interpretive programs, this thesis argues for effective ways to create 'shared histories' in practice, whilst also analysing the problems that can be encountered when trying to establish these programs.  The resulting discussion provides insights, particularly for those working in the field of interpretation, as to how heritage interpreters in Australia can adopt a more inclusive approach, that is, an approach that allows for multiple voices both from and about the past, to be heard.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Electronic reproduction.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>viii, 265 p., bound : ill. ; 30 cm.</dc:description>
    <dc:subject>Aboriginal Australians</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Historic preservation</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Cultural property</dc:subject>
    <dc:relation type="original">Also available in print form.</dc:relation>
    <dc:identifier>http:// ... lib.mq.edu.au/catalogue/erthesis/748905</dc:identifier>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description>
    <dc:title>The process and organisational consequences of new artefact adoption in surgery [electronic resource] /</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>Johnstone, Patricia Lynne.</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>Macquarie University.Macquarie Graduate School of Management.</dc:creator>
    <dc:type manuscript="yes">text</dc:type>
    <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2001.</dc:date>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:description>Surgical technologies since the late 1980s have undergone substantial innovations that have involved ...the adoption of new machines, instruments, and related surgical materials... referred to throughtout this thesis as intra-operative artefacts... typically represents a commitment of substantial financial resources by the hospitals concerned. However, little is documented about the process whereby the decisions are made to adopt new intra-operative artefacts, and no previous research appears to have explored the work-related consequences of new intra-operative artefact adoption within operating theatre services. This thesis explores the reasons why new intra-operative artefacts are adopted, how the decisions are made, who are the participants in the decsion process and what are the expected and actual organisational consequences of new intra-operative artefact adoption.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Thesis (PhD)--Macquarie University, 2001.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Bibliography: leaves 288-310.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Introduction -- Introduction to research problem and methodology -- Study context -- Theoretical framework - Review of the literature -- Study design and methods -- Study sites, surgical procedures, and labour input to surgical production -- New intra-operative artefacts: goals, choices and consequences -- Conclusion.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Surgical technologies since the late 1980s have undergone substantial innovations that have involved ...the adoption of new machines, instruments, and related surgical materials... referred to throughtout this thesis as intra-operative artefacts... typically represents a commitment of substantial financial resources by the hospitals concerned. However, little is documented about the process whereby the decisions are made to adopt new intra-operative artefacts, and no previous research appears to have explored the work-related consequences of new intra-operative artefact adoption within operating theatre services. This thesis explores the reasons why new intra-operative artefacts are adopted, how the decisions are made, who are the participants in the decsion process and what are the expected and actual organisational consequences of new intra-operative artefact adoption.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Electronic reproduction.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>xii, 347 leaves, bound :</dc:description>
    <dc:subject>Surgical technology</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Operating rooms</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Hospitals</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Surgical instruments and apparatus</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Hospitals</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Technological change -- decision process.</dc:subject>
    <dc:relation type="original">Also available in print form.</dc:relation>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description>
    <dc:title>The fragile state of the European Union (EU) [electronic resource] : its battle for survival with the Member States /</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>Fox, James.</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>Macquarie University.Dept. of Politics.</dc:creator>
    <dc:type manuscript="yes">text</dc:type>
    <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2006.</dc:date>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:description>The European Union (EU) is partly supranational and partly inter-governmental.  It is dependent on the concurrance of all its Member States for the important decisions required for the running of the EU.  This causes an inherent instability in the EU.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Thesis (Masters)--Macquarie University (Division of Humanitites, Department of Politics), 2006.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Bibliography: p. 215-231.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>The fragile state of the European Union (EU), its battle for survival with the Member States. -- The growth of the EU and the gradual transfer of powers from the Member States. -- The impact of the European Court of Justice. -- The formation of policy communities and multi-level governance. -- The Commission's sole right to initiate legislation and its reference to subsidiarity. -- The all-powerful Competition Directorate, which has an influential section of economic purists. -- The increased powers of the European Parliament and its shortcomings. -- The reluctance of national governments to adopt progressive attitudes and to let the Commission change its policies and procedures. -- The national contributions to the EU budget. -- The taxation differences between the various Member States. -- The EU constitution. -- The demographic development. -- Regional development and the structural funds. -- Competition policy. -- The Common Agricultural Policy. -- The Common Environment Policy. -- Economic and Monetary Union (EMU), the Euro, the Stability and Growth Pact (SGP) and the European Central Bank. -- Transport. -- The Common Energy Policy. -- The Area of Freedom, Security and Justice (AFSJ).</dc:description>
    <dc:description>The European Union (EU) is partly supranational and partly inter-governmental.  It is dependent on the concurrance of all its Member States for the important decisions required for the running of the EU.  This causes an inherent instability in the EU.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Electronic reproduction.</dc:description>
    <dc:subject>European Union.</dc:subject>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description>
    <dc:title>Source authentication in group communication [electronic resource] /</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>Al-Ibrahim, Mohamed Hussain</dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>Macquarie University.Dept. of Computing.</dc:creator>
    <dc:type manuscript="yes">text</dc:type>
    <dc:publisher></dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>2005.</dc:date>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:description>Multicast is a relatively new and emerging communication mode in which a sender sends a message to a group of recipients in just one connection establishment... reducing broadband overhead and increasing resource utilization in the already congested and contented network...  The focus of the research in this area has been in two directions: first, building an efficient routing infrastructure, and secondly, building a sophisticated security infrastructure. The focus of this work is on the second issue.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>An ideal authenticated multicast environment ... provides authenticity for all the communication operations in the system... We ...  propose a comprehensive solution to the problem ... for all its possible operations... 1. one-to-one (or joining mode) 2. one-to-many (or broadcast mode) 3. many-to-one (or concast mode) 4. intermediate (or transit mode) ... We study the ... mode known as anycast, in which a server is selected from a group of servers. Further we develop ... schemes for group-based communication exploiting the distinct features of one-time signatures... cover situations when a threshold number of participants are involved and ... where a proxy signer is required.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Thesis (PhD)--Macquarie University (Division of Information &amp; Communication Sciences, Department of Computing), 2004.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Title from screen page; viewed 10 Oct 2005.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Bibliography: leaves 163-175.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Introduction -- Cryptographic essentials -- Multicast: structure and security -- Authentication of multicast streams -- Authentication of concast communication -- Authentication of transit flows -- One-time signatures for authenticating group communication -- Authentication of anycast communication -- Authentication of joining operation - Conclusion and future directions.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Electronic publication; full text available in PDF format.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Multicast is a relatively new and emerging communication mode in which a sender sends a message to a group of recipients in just one connection establishment... reducing broadband overhead and increasing resource utilization in the already congested and contented network...  The focus of the research in this area has been in two directions: first, building an efficient routing infrastructure, and secondly, building a sophisticated security infrastructure. The focus of this work is on the second issue.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>An ideal authenticated multicast environment ... provides authenticity for all the communication operations in the system... We ...  propose a comprehensive solution to the problem ... for all its possible operations... 1. one-to-one (or joining mode) 2. one-to-many (or broadcast mode) 3. many-to-one (or concast mode) 4. intermediate (or transit mode) ... We study the ... mode known as anycast, in which a server is selected from a group of servers. Further we develop ... schemes for group-based communication exploiting the distinct features of one-time signatures... cover situations when a threshold number of participants are involved and ... where a proxy signer is required.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Electronic reproduction.</dc:description>
    <dc:description></dc:description>
    <dc:subject>Authentication.</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Digital signatures.</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Computer networks</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Data encryption (Computer science)</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Computers</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Cryptography.</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Computer security.   alibrahim@kuc01.kuniv.edu.kw&gt;</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Computer network protocols.</dc:subject>
    <dc:relation type="original">Also available in a print form.</dc:relation>
    <dc:identifier>http://lachesis.lib.mq.edu.au/catalogue/erthesis/728917.pdf</dc:identifier>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>